- Professor Ragheeb.   - Send him in, will you?
- 拉吉卜教授  - 带他进来,好吗？
Good afternoon. Mr. Saeed?
下午好。赛义德先生
Mr. Saeed's away, I'm afraid. My name's Sloane.
赛义德先生不在,很抱歉。我叫斯隆
Away? Why is he away?
不在？他为什么不在？
Flu, Professor.
流感,教授
Medical men aren't immune. He asked me to look after his appointments.
医生也不能幸免,你知道。他让我负责他的门诊预约
I'm only checking your glasses. You look as though I want to drill your teeth.
我只是检查你的眼镜。你看起来好像我要钻你的牙齿
Do sit down, Professor.
哦,务必要坐下来,教授
Ragheeb. That doesn't sound English. Are you English, Professor Ragheeb?
拉吉卜,那听起来不像英语。你是英国人吗,拉吉卜教授？
- Why do you ask?   - Oh, small talk, merely small talk.
- 为什么,你为什么这么问？  - 哦,闲聊,闲聊而已
The weather's too dull and politics too explosive.
天气太乏味,而政治太容易引起争论
I certainly didn't mean to pry.
我当然不是故意要去打听
- May I see your glasses?   - I can't see anything without them.
- 我能看看你的眼镜吗？  - 没有它们我什么也看不见
- Yes. Yes, indeed.   - Please.
- 是的。是的,的确如此  - 行了吧
- Have you been exposed to flu recently?   - Does that weaken the eyes?
- 你最近接触到流感了吗？  - 那会使视力下降吗？
No, merely the eye doctors.
不会,仅仅是眼科医生
There's so much close personal contact in our line, we can't be too careful.
在我们活动区域内有太多的密切接触,我们越小心越好
Now...
现在...
let's just try these.
我们试试这些
There.
那里
- Read those letters in the mirror.   - "A."
- 读出镜子里的字母,好吗？  - “A”
"N, D."
“N, D.”
"A, O, H, T."
“A, O, H, T.”
Not bad. Now the other eye.
不错。现在另一只眼睛
"H, C, U."
“H, C, U.”
"D, H, L, E."
“D, H, L, E.”
- "M." No. "N."   - Jolly good.
- “M.”不“N.”  - 非常好
Look up at me, Professor. I want to put some drops in your eyes.
抬头看我,教授。我想往你的眼睛里滴些药水
- Why?   - To dilate the pupil.
- 为什么？  - 扩张瞳孔
It's quite all right, Professor. You won't feel anything.
真的没事,教授。你不会有任何感觉
- There. That didn't hurt, did it?   - No, it was...
- 那,那以前不疼,是吧？  - 是的,以前不...
Here on the final slide
现在这是最后的一张幻灯片
is an example of a more cursive form of hieroglyphs,
是象形文字中更近于草书的一个范例
probably from the reign of the great Pharaoh Ramses II.
大概来自于伟大的法老拉美西斯二世统治时期
Now we can still recognize what many of the signs represent.
现在我们仍然可以认出这里的许多标志代表什么
Here, for example, is the word for "heart",
例如这里,这个是“心”字
written simply with the picture of the heart.
简单地用心的图画来写出
But here, above the monster Amensit,
但这里,怪物的上方,
who, as you can see, is part crocodile, part lion and part hippo,
一个坐着的人,正如你能看到的那个人,一部分是鳄鱼
and who waits to devour the heart of the dead man
一部分是狮子,一部分是河马,他正在等待吞噬死者的心
is the glyph for a house.
这是一个代表房子的雕文
Below it is a mouth. These signs have phonetic value only.
在它下面是一张嘴。这些符号只代表音值
They are followed by a drawing of a pair of legs,
跟在后面的是一双腿的绘图
which, in this case, has no phonetic value.
在这种情况下,它没有音值
As an ideogram, it does give us the clue to the meaning of the word
然而作为表意文字,它确实给了我们这个词的含义的线索
"to go forth".
意思是“往前走”
Sex.
性
I thought there must be some way of attracting your attention, Mr. Fanshaw.
我想一定有别的办法能吸引你的注意,范肖先生
I seem to have been talking in your sleep.
我似乎一直在与你梦中交谈
That will be all for today. Professor Ragheeb will be back tomorrow.
今天就这些。拉吉卜教授明天会回来
Good morning.
再会
May I have a word, Professor Pollock?
我能和你说句话吗,波洛克教授？
If it's about that outstanding bill at the bookstore,
如果是关于那张在书店未付钱的账单,
there's a simple explanation: poverty.
有一个简单的解释：贫困
- No, it's nothing like that.   - In that case, how do you do?
- 不,不是那样的  - 哦,那样的话,你怎么做？
My name is Sloane. Major Sylvester Pennington Sloane
我叫斯隆,教授。西尔威斯特·彭宁顿·斯隆少校
of Her Majesty's 42nd Highland Fusiliers, retired.
来自皇家第四十二高地步兵团,已经退役
- Marvelous.   - Yes, quite.
- 了不起  - 哦,是的,的确
I'm private secretary to Mr. Nejim Beshraavi of the shipping lines.
我是一位私人秘书,就职于纳吉姆·拜士拉维先生的航运公司
- The Nejim Beshraavi.   - I didn't think there could be two.
- 嗯,纳吉姆·拜士拉维  - 我没想到你有两个职位
Mr. Beshraavi would like to see you in London,
拜士拉维先生就在伦敦,他想见你
so if you'll follow me, please, the car is waiting.
所以如果你跟我走的话,车已经准备好了
Mr. Sloane, this is Wednesday. Shall I tell you about my Wednesdays?
斯隆先生,今天是星期三。要我告诉你我怎么过星期三吗？
Right now: a healthy jog and a couple of tutorials,
现在需要一个健康的慢跑,然后有几节辅导课,
an indescribable lunch with the faculty at 12:45...
和老师们在十二点三刻的美妙午餐
Mr. Beshraavi will pay you well for your time.
拜士拉维先生会为你的时间支付一大笔钱
And I could use it, I don't mind telling you.
我需要钱,这没什么可隐瞒的
But, as I said, not on Wednesdays.
但就像我说的,星期三不行
Good morning, Mr. Sloane.
再会,斯隆先生
You people really can't take no for an answer, can you?
你们真是执着无畏的一群人,是吗？
What do you think you're doing?
你们觉得你们在做什么？
Let me go!
让我走！
Good Lord, a-aren't you...
我的天,你不是...
Mr. Pollock, may I present His Excellency, Mr. Hassan Jena?
波洛克先生,我能介绍这位阁下吗？哈桑·耶拿先生
- Well... Mr. Prime Minister.   - Good morning, Mr. Pollock.
- 好吧...首相先生  - 早上好,波洛克先生
I am Mr. Jena's Ambassador to Great Britain, Mohammed Lufti.
我是耶拿先生的驻英大使,穆罕默德·勒夫特
Mr. Ambassador.
大使先生
Please forgive this unorthodox method of making your acquaintance.
我请求你原谅这种不同寻常的结识方式
Please, don't mention it.
哦,请不要客气,首相先生
There's nothing like a kidnapping now and then to keep the circulation going.
没有什么能像现在来一次绑架更会使血液保持循环了
The fact is that there are very few men on this Earth
哦,事实是这个地球上很少有人
whom I admire more than you.
比我更加钦佩你
You're a very great man.
你是一个很伟大的人
No man is greater than the people he serves. Your respect must be for them.
没有人比他所要服务的人更伟大,波洛克先生。你必须尊重他们
Yes, sir. I... I didn't know that you were in England.
是的,先生。我...我不知道你在英国
You are quite right. I am not. You have not seen me.
你完全正确,我不在。你没见到我
The first favor I would ask of you is to help keep my visit here a secret.
我请你帮的第一个忙是帮助我在英国秘密访问
Of course, sir. And... And the second?
当然,先生。那么...那么第二个呢？
You know a fellow countryman of mine, Mr. Nejim Beshraavi.
你知道我的一个同胞,纳吉姆·拜士拉维先生
The Nejim Beshraavi.
那位纳吉姆·拜士拉维
Yes, our richest and most powerful citizen.
是的,我们最有钱有势的公民
We have every reason to believe
我们有一切理由相信
he intends approaching you with a business proposition.
他为了一笔生意而有意地接近你
He already has, sir, but I turned him down.
哦,他找过我了,先生。但不担心,我,我拒绝了他
- Oh, dear.   - Wrong?
- 哦,天啊  - 做错了吗？
Your association with him could have been valuable to the cause of freedom.
你与拜士拉维交往可能对自由事业有极大的价值,教授
How?
怎么做？
All we know is that Beshraavi is opposed to our programmes
我们所知道的是拜士拉维反对我们的方案和计划
and plans some violent exercise of that opposition in the near future.
不远的将来,反对派会发起暴力运动
We have to find out what he intends doing and when.
我们得查出他打算做什么,何时做
You want me to re-establish contact,
你们要我重新建立联系
accept his offer and see what I can find out?
接受他的建议,然后看我们能查出什么？
We want that very much.
我们非常需要这些
But you must not accept until you know all the possibilities.
但是你在知道所有可能性之前,不能接受
The assignment carries a certain amount of risk.
这项工作有一定的风险
Is that a statesmanlike way of saying that I could get killed?
按政治家的说法,我有可能被杀害吧
Mr. Beshraavi respects no one's life but his own.
拜士拉维先生不尊重任何人的生命,除了他自己的
If you wish, I will stop the car and let you out with nothing further being said.
如果你愿意,我会停下车,然后放你出去,不会再说一句话
For generations, the Pollocks have devoted themselves
波洛克家族的世世代代
to uncovering the past.
投身于揭露过去
I think it's probably about time that a Pollock
我想也许是时候让波洛克
involved himself in the future for a change.
投身于未来,做一次改变
As soon as you have any information, you will contact Mr. Jena in London.
你一有任何消息,就马上联系伦敦的耶拿先生
Ambassador-2779.
大使 2779
Words cannot express my gratitude.
言语无法表达我的感激之情
Mr. Pollock, very good of you to reconsider my proposal.
波洛克先生,你能重新考虑我的建议可真好
I always try my best to cooperate with the very rich, Mr. Beshraavi.
我总是尽力和非常富有的拜士拉维先生合作
Do sit down.
请坐
You mustn't mind Hassan, Mr. Pollock.
以一定不会介意哈桑,波洛克先生
- Hassan?   - He's a peregrine falcon.
- 哈桑？  - 它是一只猎鹰
I've named him Hassan Jena after our beloved prime minister.
我叫它哈桑·耶拿是鉴于我们敬爱的首相
They share so many sterling qualities.
他们身上有很多优秀的品质
A sharp eye, a fierce dedication, and very sharp claws.
敏锐的目光,狂热的奉献,和非常锋利的爪子
Hassan won't harm you, Mr. Pollock, if you don't separate him from his master.
哈桑不会伤害你,波洛克先生,只要你不去尝试把它和它的主人分开
He is excessively loyal.
它极其忠诚
You keep him well fed, I trust.
我相信你把它喂得很好
Of course. Nobody's that loyal.
当然。没有人如此忠诚
I won't presume upon your time, Professor.
我不会滥用你的时间,教授
I know how valuable it must be.
我知道它一定很宝贵
What do you make of that?
你是怎么理解的？
It's a copy of a Hittite inscription.
这是一份希泰语题词的副本
Second millennium BC, I would guess.
我猜是在公元前两千年
Take a date, Mr. Pollock, as a gesture of friendship.
尝一尝,波洛克先生,为了表示友谊
I'm a very Arabian Arab, I'm afraid.
我恐怕是一个地道的阿拉伯人
Friends?
是朋友吗？
Flesh, Mr. Pollock. Hassan eats only flesh.
肉,波洛克先生。哈桑只吃肉
- I thought he looked at it wistfully.   - It must have been your fingers.
- 我以为它在若有所思地看着它  - 那一定是你的手指,教授
I want to know what that inscription means.
我想知道那些题词是什么意思
I want to know that very much.
我非常想知道
May I ask an indelicate question?
我能问一个无礼的问题吗？
- How much?   - $25,000.
- 多少钱？  - 两万五千美元
Very well. I won't quibble, $30,000.
好吧。我不会斤斤计较,三万美元
You go right ahead and quibble.
你可以随便斤斤计较
How did you happen to get hold of it?
你怎么得到它的
Let us say, I happened upon it by chance.
可以这样说,我偶然发现它的
Oh.
哦
Well, may the... gods continue to smile on you.
好吧,祝愿...上帝继续对你微笑
Thank you, Professor. I value your good wishes.
谢谢你,教授。我珍视你的美好祝愿
But I won't keep you from your work any longer.
但我不想再耽误你的工作了
If you haven't finished by 8:00 tonight, you'll be...
如果你今晚八点还没完成,你会...
- Tonight?   - That is correct.
- 今晚？  - 没错
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to interrupt your threat.
对不起。我不是有意打断你的恐吓
- If I'm not finished by 8:00...   - Then you'll be my guest for dinner.
- 如果我八点之前不能完成...  - 那么你就会是我的晚餐客人
I see.
我明白了
If I should happen to run just a smidge over?
如果我只弄懂了一点点的内容大意
You'll find this house a comfortable place to work in, Mr. Pollock,
你会发现这栋房子是一个舒适的工作场所,波洛克先生
however long it takes you.
无论你需要多长时间
- Hello.   - Hello.
- 你好  - 你好
Hello.
你好
Hello, hello, hello.
你好,你好,你好
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
Oh, these English crosswords are devilish, don't you think?
哦,这些英文字谜是可怕的,你不觉得吗？
- You're an American.   - Yes, sir. Indeedy-do, ma'am.
- 你是美国人  - 是的,先生。当然是,夫人
I don't meet many Americans.
我没见过很多美国人
Actually, I don't meet many people who are dressed like that either.
其实,我也没见过很多穿得像你这样的
Do you like it?
你喜欢它吗？
Would you do me up, please?
你能帮我拉上吗？
- Oh.   - Can you manage?
- 哦  - 你能行吗？
Well, I... I always tremble when I'm happy.
好吧,我...我高兴的时候总是发抖
- I take it you're a houseguest here.   - Why do you take that?
- 我猜你是这里的客人  - 你为什么这么认为？
One doesn't usually arrive for high tea dressed in a nighty.
没有人会穿着睡衣来喝傍晚茶
One also isn't a houseguest in one's own house.
没有人是自己的房子的客人
Oh, it's your house. I got the impression it was Mr. Beshraavi's house.
哦,这是你的房子。我得到的印象是这是拜士拉维先生的房子
Nejim gives that impression with everything he borrows,
纳吉姆给人的印象是他什么都借
but I assure you it is my house, and he's the guest.
但我向你保证,这是我的房子,并且他是客人
Would you care to stay for dinner?
你愿意留下吃晚饭吗？
I'm afraid that our street urchin has already invited me.
恐怕我们的街头顽童已经邀请我了
How bothersome.
多令人讨厌
You are working on the cipher, aren't you?
你在为密文而工作,是不是？
Let's not talk about work. Let's talk about you.
我们不要谈工作。我们来谈谈你
Listen, I don't know what Nejim has told you...
听着,我不知道纳吉姆告诉你什么了
There you are, Yasmin. I hardly expected to find you here.
你在这,亚丝明。我没想到会在这找到你
- In her own house?   - In the library.
- 你是说在她自己的房子吗？  - 在书房
Yasmin has so many talents, she has practically no time for reading.
亚丝明这么有天赋,她几乎没有时间阅读
I'm sorry to tell you this, my dear, but Mr. Pollock is as poor as a church mouse.
我很抱歉不得不告诉你,我亲爱的。但波洛克先生穷得像教堂里的老鼠
- Will you come and change for dinner?   - Excuse me.
- 你愿意来换件衣服去吃晚饭吗？  - 失陪了
Those slippers are absolutely beautiful, my darling.
这双拖鞋真漂亮,我亲爱的
- Are you wearing them for my benefit?   - Of course.
- 你是为我穿的吗？  - 当然,纳吉姆
Mr. Pollock does not have your exotic refinements.
波洛克先生没有你这种奇异的风雅
- He prefers nighties.   - She said it, I didn't.
- 他更喜欢睡衣  - 她说的,我没说
Mr. Pollock, some Bedouins are in the habit of saying to their guests,
波洛克先生,有些流浪者习惯对他们的客人说
"All that I possess is yours".
“我所拥有的都是你的”
I am not one of them.
我不是其中之一
Delicious, Beshraavi. What is it, squab?
美味可口,拜士维拉。这是什么,乳鸽吗？
- Lark.   - Lark? Good heavens.
- 云雀  - 云雀？天啊
They've been soaked in honey for eight days.
他们整整在蜂蜜里浸泡了八天
What about you, Mr. Pollock? Or is the prospect too exotic?
你呢,波洛克先生？还是景象过于奇异了
I trust you'll notify my next of kin.
好吧,我信任你会通知我的至亲
Go on, Mr. Pollock. Courage.
来吧,波洛克先生。胆量
Oh, I am sorry.
哦,对不起
That's all right. I've always had a sweet tooth.
哦,没事。我一贯喜欢甜食
I hate being clumsy. I despise it.
我讨厌笨手笨脚的。我鄙视它
But you never are, my dear.
但你从来也不笨拙。我亲爱的
This is the first time I've seen you be so gauche.
这是我第一次看到你如此笨拙
You've dropped something, Mr. Pollock.
你东西掉了,波洛克先生
Well... so I have at that.
好吧... 是我那时掉的
What do you suppose it is?
你觉得那是什么？
It looks like a little piece of folded paper, doesn't it?
这看起来像一小片折叠的纸,不是吗？
Let's see if there's anything written on it.
我们看看上面有没有写什么
Was that you? I'm terribly sorry.
哦,叉到你了吗？我非常抱歉
Let's see if there's anything written on it.
我们看看上面有没有写什么
There is something written on it.
上面写着一些东西
Don't keep it a secret. What is it?
不要保守秘密,波洛克先生。写的什么？
It's a prescription.
这是一个药方
I suffer from indigestion.
哦,我消化不良
All those dry books I try to digest.
就像去消化那些枯燥无味的书
Perhaps we can have it made up at the chemist just around the corner.
也许我们可以带你去附近药店调理。是不是,我亲爱的
- Don't bother.   - No bother. One of the servants...
- 没事,不用麻烦了  - 不麻烦。我会叫一个仆人
It would be for them. It's absolutely unnecessary.
很麻烦他们,这绝对没有必要
I think I'd better be getting back to work.
好吧。我想我得回去工作了
The dinner was delicious, and... that was quite a lark.
晚餐很可口,而且...十分令人开心
Well...
好吧...
He certainly was strange, even for an American.
他确实很奇怪,即使是美国人
I'm sure you and Mr. Beauchamp have business to discuss,
我敢肯定你和比彻姆先生有事要讨论
so I'll develop a splitting headache before your talk gives me one.
那会使我头疼欲裂,我就先行告辞了
- Good night, Mr. Beauchamp.   - Good night, Miss Azir.
- 晚安,比彻姆先生  - 晚安,阿兹尔小姐
When are you going to let me show you around my bank?
你什么时候让我带你去参观我的银行
The moment I find myself in need of refinancing.
我发现自己需要重新募集资金的时候
You, I'll see later, no doubt.
我们想必要待会儿见
Beauchamp, you've been oozing good fellowship all evening.
好吧,比彻姆。你整晚都洋溢着良好的伙伴关系
When a banker oozes, someone's in trouble.
当银行家充分表露时,有人会有麻烦
Let us have your bad news.
告诉我们你的坏消息
I was too discreet to mention it in front of your guests,
我非常慎重,不想在客人面前提到它
but do you know what they've been saying about you on the exchange?
但你知道他们对你的交易说些什么吗？
Your brokers gossip like Arab women at the well.
你经纪人的绯闻就像井里阿拉伯妇女
They say when Prime Minister Jena arrives the day after tomorrow,
他们说当首相后天到达耶拿后
he will sign the treaty.
他将签署条约
They say the treaty specifies Anglo-American finance
他们说该条约指定的是英美金融
in return for a promise your country uses English and American tankers.
作为承诺,你的国家要使用英国和美国的油轮
They say your ships will be laid up for good.
他们说你的船可以安闲地休憩
- Do they?   - If they go on saying that, old boy,
- 他们就是这么说的？  - 好吧,如果他们继续那么说,老伙计
in a week your shares will be down ten points.
截至本周你的股票会下跌十点
Don't worry. There will be no treaty signed, old boy.
别担心。将不会签署任何条约,老伙计
I happen to have in my employ a most dependable soothsayer.
我恰巧雇用了一位最可靠的预言家
Psst. In here.
嘘,在这
Now then, Miss Azir, I wonder if you'd tell me what this is all about.
那么,阿兹尔小姐,我想你能否告诉我这是怎么回事
Call me Yasmin. At least while you're in my bathroom.
叫我亚丝明。至少当你在我的浴室时
Now then, Yasmin, I wonder if you would tell me what is going on?
那么,亚丝明,我想你能否告诉我发生什么事了？
Professor Ragheeb didn't fall out of any window.
拉吉卜教授没有从任何窗户坠落
They murdered him!
他们谋杀了他！
Beshraavi?
拜士拉维吗？
I doubt if it was him personally.
我怀疑是不是他亲自干的
- How do you know?   - What difference does it make?
- 你怎么知道？  - 有什么不同吗？
They killed him, and they'll kill you too. You'd better keep out of this.
他们杀了他,而且他们也会杀了你。你最好别介入此事
Me? Why should Beshraavi have anything against me?
我？为什么拜士拉维要对付我？
He needs me to decipher the inscription.
它需要我破译题词
- And when you've done it?   - Good point.
- 你完成之后呢？  - 问得好
The message is too important for anyone he doesn't own to know about it.
那消息除了他自己任何人知道都不行
What about you?
你呢？
Lock, stock and barrel?
毫无顾忌吗？
This is ridiculous.
这太荒谬了
We're in England, a civilized country, in the middle of London.
我们在英国,文明的国家,就在伦敦的中部
Over there is Regent's Park. There's the zoo.
那边是摄政公园,那边是动物园
Over in Buckingham Palace, the Queen is probably playing Scrabble.
在白金汉宫,女王可能在玩拼字游戏
He can't own anyone here.
他不能主宰这里的任何人
Everyone has his price.
每个人都有自己的价值
How much, Mr. Pollock?
什么价钱,波洛克先生？
$30,000.
三万美元
I did not settle so cheaply.
我算的可没这么便宜
Why should you care what happens to me?
你为什么要关心发生在我身上的事？
I care about all things that live, Professor.
我关心所有生物,教授
$30,000 in exchange for your old age is a very bad bargain.
用三万美元交换你这把年纪是一笔赔本的买卖
Do you know...
你知道吗...
- Who is it?   - Yasmin, why have you locked the door?
- 是谁？  - 亚丝明,你为什么把门锁上
Yasmin? Can you hear me?
亚丝明？你听得见吗？
I was about to take a shower, darling.
我正在洗澡,亲爱的
You know how I despise locked doors.
你知道我多么鄙视上锁的门
Forgive me, Nejim.
原谅我,纳吉姆
People who lock doors generally have things to hide.
通常锁门的人有事情要隐瞒
Would you care to search me?
你要不要来搜搜我？
Would I find your thoughts?
我能发觉你的想法吗？
Well?
好吃吗？
Darling, don't ask me to speak with my mouth full.
亲爱的,别让我满嘴食物地说话
You know, at dinner, just for a moment,
你知道吗,吃晚餐时,就在那一刻
I thought you deliberately knocked over the plate and gave a note to Mr. Pollock.
我以为你故意打翻了盘子,然后给了波洛克先生一张便条
Imagine. That really is extraordinary.
想象,那真是非同寻常
- Jealous? You?   - I'm jealous of your thoughts, Yasmin.
- 妒忌吗？你？  - 我妒忌你的思想,亚丝明
I'm jealous of everything I can't see or hear. Your shower's still running.
我妒忌一切我看不到和听不到的。你的淋浴器还在开着
- I'll turn it off.   - No, take your shower.
- 我去关掉它  - 不,去洗你的澡
Maybe I won't tonight. I'm so sleepy.
也许我今晚不会洗了。我很想睡觉
In that case, please do. I want you wide awake.
那样的话,请去洗吧。我想让你完全清醒
There now. Wasn't I right? Isn't that refreshing?
好了,我说得对吗？那是不是很提神？
You might say that.
你可以这么说
- You feel wide awake now?   - Yes... but I wish I weren't.
- 你现在觉得完全清醒了吗？  - 是的...但我希望我没有
You sound very tense, my love. Turn around.
你听起来很紧张,我的宝贝。转过身
Let the water run down your back.
让水从你的背部流下
- It soothes the nerves.   - I don't think it would.
- 舒缓神经  - 我不认为会
- Nejim?   - Yes?
- 纳吉姆？  - 怎么了？
Why is Mr. Pollock working on that inscription?
为什么波洛克先生要着手题词的工作？
It's a business matter. It would only bore you.
这是一个商业问题,我的宝贝。这只会让你厌烦
- What was that?   - I dropped the soap.
- 那是什么？  - 我把肥皂弄掉了
- Should I pick it up?   - Oh, no, no, I... I'll manage.
- 你想让我帮你捡起来吗？  - 哦,不,不,我...我能行
Somehow.
想个办法
- Have you got it?   - Yes, darling. It's all right.
- 你捡到了吗？  - 是的,亲爱的。没事了
Extraordinary sensation. Perhaps it was the way he looked at you.
非凡的感觉。也许这是他看你的样子
- Who?   - Pollock.
- 谁？  - 波洛克
Darling, if you start getting jealous over everyone who looks at me,
亲爱的,如果谁看我都会使你开始妒忌
it will do terrible things to your blood pressure.
那对你的血压是可怕的事情
I don't think you have to worry about college professors.
但我认为你不必为大学教授担心
- Why not?   - They're only interested in work.
- 为什么不必？  - 他们只对工作感兴趣
They're the most dangerous kind, my love. They're such expert peekers.
他们是最危险的一类,我的宝贝。他们是窥视专家
Don't worry. If I were standing stark naked in front of Mr. Pollock,
别担心。如果我赤身裸体地站在波洛克先生的面前,
he'd probably yawn.
他也许会打哈欠
I think it's time I dried you.
我想是时候让我来给你擦干了
Excuse me, Yasmin. The phone.
对不起,亚丝明。有电话
- Yes?   - Mr. Beshraavi.
- 是的  - 拜士拉维先生
Yes, what is it, Sloane?
是的,什么事,斯隆？
I don't know where Mr. Pollock is, sir.
我不知道波洛克先生在哪,先生
- Isn't he in the library?   - I don't think so, sir.
- 他不在书房吗？  - 我不这样认为,先生
He was your responsibility.
他是由你负责的
- What about the cipher?   - I don't know, sir.
- 密文呢？  - 我不知道,先生
Well, go and check.
好吧,去检查一下
Yes, sir.
是的,先生
- Mr. Pollock.   - Yes?
- 波洛克先生  - 是的
- Do you have the inscription?   - It's in my pocket.
- 你有那个题词吗？  - 在我口袋里
I hope it's written with waterproof ink.
好吧,我希望是用防水墨写的
- It isn't there.   - It isn't there?
- 它不在那  - 它不在那
Must you mismanage everything?
你一定要把一切都处置失当吗？
I don't know where Mr. Pollock is either.
我也不知道波洛克先生在哪
What do you mean? You've got to find him!
找不到是什么意思？你必须找到他
Come up here at once, and bring that butler of hers!
立刻来这,并把她的男管家带来
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
- This is no time for dessert.   - Well, they're good.
- 这没有时间吃甜点  - 好吧,好吧,它们很好
- Here, have one.   - Come on. Come on.
- 给,来一块  - 快点,快点
- He is not on the ground floor, sir.   - You searched every room?
- 他不在一楼,先生  - 你查了每个房间吗？
Every room, sir.
每个房间吗,先生
Sloane, Pollock was in your charge.
斯隆,波洛克是由你负责的
I trusted you.
我相信你
- Now, you. What's your name?   - Hemsley, sir.
- 现在,你。你叫什么名字？  - 赫姆斯利,先生
Hemsley. Yes, of course.
赫姆斯利。是的,当然
- What have you been up to, Hemsley?   - N-Nothing, sir.
- 现在你都干了什么,赫姆斯利？  - 没-没什么,先生
Have you been disobeying my orders?
你一直在违抗我的命令吗？
I-I work for Miss Azir, sir.
我-我在为阿兹尔小姐工作,先生
So you do. I appreciate loyalty, Hemsley.
啊,所以你。我欣赏忠诚,赫姆斯利
Tell me, how would you like to work for me?
告诉我,你愿意为我工作吗？
I'm satisfied with my present position, thank you.
我对目前的岗位很满意,谢谢你,拜士拉维先生
Are you?
是吗？
Please tell me when you're dissatisfied with it, Hemsley.
如果你不满意,请告诉我,赫姆斯利
Welcome aboard, Hemsley.
欢迎加入,赫姆斯利
Thank you, sir.
谢谢你,先生
Don't worry, Hemsley. Here's a bonus.
别担心,赫姆斯利。这是奖金
Oh. Well, thank you, sir.
哦,好的,谢谢你,先生
Don't mention it, Hemsley. Would you like another bonus?
别客气,赫姆斯利。你想再要一笔奖金吗？
Oh, not just now, sir, if you don't mind, sir.
哦,不是现在,先生,如果你不介意的话,先生
- Where's Mr. Pollock?   - He came up here, sir.
- 波洛克先生在哪？  - 他来这了,先生
Up here?
来这了
- Where up here?   - To this room, sir.
- 来这什么地方了？  - 来这个房间了,先生
No hanky-panky, Mr. Beshraavi.
不许耍花招,拜士拉维先生
From man or bird.
无论是人还是鸟
Believe him, Nejim. He means it. He said he'd kill me.
相信他,纳吉姆。他是认真的。他说他会杀了我
Close the door, lady.
关门,女士
Lock it.
锁上
Get him, Mustafa.
抓住他,穆斯塔法
But carefully. Whatever he does to Miss Azir,
但要小心。无论他对阿兹尔做什么,
I will do to you, personally.
我都会亲自地以同样的方式对待你
Don't think that I haven't enjoyed it. It's been a nice change.
别认为我没有得到乐趣。这是一个很好的改变
- Thanks a lot. Bye now.   - No, they won't shoot if I'm with you.
- 非常感谢。回头见  - 不,如果我和你在一起,他们就不会开枪
You still need me.
你仍然需要我
Need you? Lady, I can't live without you.
需要你？小姐,没有你我活不下去
Messy business. My apologies, miss.
肮脏的行业。我道歉,小姐
I'm sorry you had to see it.
我很抱歉让你看到它
Was I glad to see you?
我很高兴见到你
- Are you with the police?   - Inspector Webster, CID.
- 请问你是警察吗？  - 刑事调查局的韦伯斯特巡官
How in the world did you know?
你究竟是怎么知道的？
We've been watching the house. Nasty customers.
我们一直在观察房子。麻烦的客人
My house?
我的房子吗？
Yes, miss. Since Mr. Beshraavi's been staying with you.
是的,小姐。因为拜士拉维先生一直和你呆在一起
Might I suggest we move along? We'll have to get down to the station.
我可以建议我们继续前行吗？我们得去车站
All right, all right. Who's the ruddy nit who's broke my tank downstairs?
好吧,好吧。是哪个可恶的傻瓜把我楼下的水箱打碎了？
- I'm up to me neck in drowning fishes.   - There's been some trouble.
- 我正忙着处理溺水的鱼  - 抱歉,遇到了一些麻烦
Oh, and who are you? The ruddy Sheriff of Sherwood Forest?
哦,你是谁？那个可恶的舍伍德森林治安官吗？
Webster, CID.
刑事调查局的韦伯斯特
Oh. Oh, I see.
哦。哦,我知道了
You better let me see your card. I've got to make a report.
最好让我看看你的证件,我得做报告
Somebody's got to pay for them fish.
总得有人支付所有死鱼的费用
Yes, of course.
是的,当然
All right, let's go.
好了,我们走
I don't get it. Whose side are you on?
我不明白,你站在谁那一边？
What difference does it make? Let's get out of here.
有什么区别吗？让我们离开这个地方
You're not with the authorities, and you're not with Beshraavi.
你不是来自当局,而且你不是拜士维拉的人
And you can't be with Prime Minister Jena.
并且你不可能是耶拿首相的人
Who are you with?
你为谁效力？
Her.
她
Swell.
太有趣了
Ain't it a gas about my promotion?
这不是我升职的原因吗？
Number three to General Ali himself.
三号给阿里将军他本人
He's coming round, waking up.
他醒过来了,醒醒
So you're with us again, teach.
所以你又和我们在一起了,教授
I don't know whether I am or not. Whose side are you on?
我不知道我是不是。你站在谁那一边？
Don't worry about sides, daddy-o.
别担心哪一边,帅哥
Yussef Kasim is the name. Kyle Webster you've met.
我叫优素福·卡西姆。你见过凯尔·韦伯斯特
And dear Miss Azir.
还有亲爱的阿兹尔小姐
For a poor, subjugated Arab lady, you lead one hell of an emancipated life.
克服了贫苦,征服阿拉伯夫人,你领导一个完全不被束缚的生活
Mr. Beshraavi on the one hand, and Mr. Yussef Kasim on the other.
一方面是拜士拉维先生,另一方面是优素福·卡西姆先生
Do you get Sundays off?
你星期天休息吗？
Skip the college talk, teach.
略过这场学院演说,教授
To the point, daddy-o: Where is the cipher?
言归正传,帅哥：密文在哪？
- The cipher?   - Yeah, the cipher.
- 密文？  - 是的,密文
We know you've got it. No point fooling. You're in the middle of nowhere.
我们知道它在你那,没必要装傻。你现在身处荒郊野外
The Marines can't save you for democracy here.
海军陆战队无法为民主而来这拯救你
That cipher, where is it?
那个密文,它在哪？
- Ask me later, alligator.   - Where is it?
- 等会儿再问我,大鳄鱼  - 它在哪？
I left it at Beshraavi's.
哦,对了,我把它放在拜士拉维那里了
After all, it belongs to him.
毕竟,是属于他的
Wrong again, teach. He snatched it.
又错了,教授。他把它抢走的
It belongs to this cat right here.
它属于这个家伙,就在这
Where is it?
那么它在哪？
Miss Azir, after all we've been through together,
阿兹尔小姐,毕竟我们一起经历过
couldn't you find it in your heart to put in a small word on my behalf?
你怎么能忍心不替我说一句话呢？
He told me he had it in his pocket.
他告诉过我他把它放在他口袋里了
Tattletale.
打小报告
- Where is it?   - Cool it, Webster!
- 它在哪？  - 冷静,韦伯斯特！
There's a better way.
有更好的办法
Nice business associates you have, Miss Azir.
你有一个好生意伙伴,阿兹尔小姐
Why don't you tell them where it is?
你为什么不告诉他们它在哪？
Because I don't know where it is.
哦,因为我不知道它在哪
- You told me you had it.   - You told me lots of things too.
- 你告诉过我你有  - 你也告诉了我很多事情
Looks like we're just a pair of pathological liars.
看来我们只是一对病态说谎者
I was honest about one thing.
我有一件事是诚实的
I told you to keep out of this, didn't I?
我告诉过你不要介入此事,不是吗？
- That you did.   - Then why didn't you listen to me?
- 你告诉过  - 那你为什么不听我的话
Because I'm such a big know-it-all.
因为我自以为是一个无所不知的人,这就是原因
OK, teach, here's your chance to be a big "tell-it-all."
好的,教授,这有一个让你成为百事通的机会
Somehow I get the idea you've seen too much television.
不知怎么,我觉得你电视看得太多了
Webster.
韦伯斯特
Hey, Miss Azir, come on down here and I'll scrub your back.
嗨,阿兹尔小姐,快下来,我要擦洗你的背部
Professor, can you hear me?
教授,你能听到我说话吗？
An earnest professor of math studied figures while taking a bath.
一位严谨的数学教授在洗澡时研究数字
Professor, what did you do with the cipher?
教授,你是怎么处理密文的？
Cipher, cipher, who's got the cipher?
密文,密文,谁得到了密文？
- Number nine's got the cipher.   - "Nine"? What's that mean?
- 九号得到了密文  - “九”？那是什么意思？
That's for me to know and you to guess.
那是我知道的,并且是你们需要猜的
Where is it?
它在哪？
That tickles.
好痒
Professor, you can tell me. Where is the cipher?
教授,你能告诉我密文在哪吗？
Candy, I call my sugar Candy...
嗯,糖果,我叫我的宝贝糖果
This is beginning to bug me. Let's get rid of him.
这一切开始让我讨厌了,我们把他干掉
- What are you going to do?   - Dump him.
- 你打算做什么？  - 把他抛下去
- You heard him. He doesn't have it.   - Then who does?
- 你听了。他没有  - 那谁有？
That's what you're going to find out, sweet mama,
那是你要去发现的,情妇
as soon as you scoot on home and ask your rich sugar daddy. Webster.
你一赶回家,就马上问你那有钱的甜爹
Olé! Olé!
好哇！好哇！
Olé!
好哇！
Olé! Olé! Olé!
好哇！好哇！好哇！
- We were quite worried about you.   - Were you, Hemsley? How sweet.
- 我们很担心你,小姐  - 是吗,赫姆斯利？好贴心
But I expected to see you wearing a burnous by now.
但我期望看到你现在穿着连帽斗篷
I'm sorry, miss.
对不起,小姐
Don't sulk, Hemsley. I'm in no position to throw the first stone.
别生闷气,赫姆斯利。我没有资格扔第一块石头
Allah be praised, miss.
感谢真主阿拉,小姐
Yasmin, there you are.
啊,亚丝明,你在这
I'm so delighted that you've decided to come back.
我很高兴你决定回来
Your concern is so comforting, Nejim.
你的关心使我很安慰,纳吉姆
Your shower must have been quite stimulating.
你洗澡洗得一定很刺激
It was.
的确
But how do you suppose he happened to be in there, my pet?
但你认为他怎么会碰巧在那,我的宝贝？
I neglected to ask him.
我忘记问他了
All I know is he was waiting for me with those scissors when I stepped in.
我所知道的是当我走进去时,他正拿着剪刀等着我
I wonder what made him come up here in the first place?
我奇怪的是他怎么一开始就来到这？
I don't suppose it could have been your promise
我想那不可能是你的承诺
to keep him a prisoner here until he'd finished his work.
把他囚禁在这,直到他完成他的工作
Oh, dear, I hope not. I thought I was being so hospitable.
哦,亲爱的,我不希望。我以为我很好客
Westerners so often misunderstand us, don't you find?
西方人常常误解我们,你不觉得吗？
Oh, I am exhausted.
哦,我累死了
Of course you are, my poor darling.
你当然是了,我可怜的宝贝
Let me give you a massage.
让我给你按摩一下
How can you continue being so good to me when I'm such a trial?
当我叫苦连天时,你为何还对我很好
Oh, look at your poor shoes.
哦,看看你可怜的鞋
You must have done so much running.
你一定跑了很多的路
What do you suppose happened to Mustafa?
你认为穆斯塔法发生了什么事？
- He hasn't come back yet.   - Dead, I'm afraid.
- 他还没回来  - 我恐怕他死了
And servants so hard to come by these days.
仆人这些天很难过来
I saw several possible replacements at the zoo.
我在动物园看到了几个人也许能顶着
My admiration for Mr. Pollock increases.
我增加了对波洛克先生的钦佩感
Probably Mustafa didn't feel like dying.
也许穆斯塔法不想死
Mr. Pollock didn't do it, darling.
哦。不是波洛克先生干的,亲爱的
Don't stop. It feels divine.
哦,别停下来。感觉很美妙
It was Yussef Kasim.
是优素福·卡西姆
The guerrilla forces.
啊,游击队
I was wondering what they were up to.
我想知道他们想干什么
I must say, they were a little miffed at you for borrowing their cipher.
我得说他们对你有些恼火,亲爱的。因为他们把密文借给了你
I really don't think they had a chance to see it themselves.
我真的不认为他们有机会能自己看到
Roll over, my love.
翻身,我的宝贝
Do you think you can find the energy to tell me what they did to our professor?
你觉得你有精力来告诉我,他们对我们的教授做了什么？
Killed him too, I'm afraid.
我恐怕他们把他杀了
That's heaven.
那是极乐之地
- So Yussef has the cipher now?   - What makes you think that?
- 那么优素福现在得到密文了吧？  - 你怎么会这么想？
Surely they were able to make poor Mr. Pollock relinquish it.
他们无疑能让可怜的波洛克先生放弃
Mr. Pollock swore he didn't have it.
波洛克先生发誓没在他身上
Mr. Pollock was lying.
波洛克先生在撒谎
Then I'm afraid he took the truth with him to his grave.
那么我恐怕他把真相带进他的坟墓了
Before you came home I received word
你回家之前,我收到了消息
that Mr. Pollock had arrived safely at his rooms at Oxford.
波洛克先生已经安全地到达他在牛津的住所
A hardy race, the Americans.
美国人是一个勇敢的民族
I was also told that he was riding a bicycle and singing a very strange song.
还有人告诉我他骑着自行车,唱着很奇怪的歌
A hardy and fun-loving race.
一个勇敢和风趣的民族
But tell me, my flower, I don't think you've explained yet
但告诉我,我的花朵,我想你还没有解释
how it happens that Yussef managed to leave you alive.
优素福怎么会让你活着离开
It's very simple, really. I promised I'd work with him.
真的很简单,我答应和他一起工作
- By spying on me, you mean?   - Of course.
- 你是说监视我吗？  - 当然
- How very amusing.   - Isn't it?
- 多么有趣  - 不是吗？
- Marvelous, in fact.   - I knew you'd enjoy it.
- 事实上很了不起  - 我知道你会喜欢
- Darling?   - Yes, precious?
- 亲爱的？  - 是的,宝贝？
- You are hurting my shoulders.   - Am I? Oh, I'm so sorry.
- 你把我的肩膀弄疼了  - 是吗？哦,我很抱歉
- Better?   - Much.
- 好点了吗？  - 好多了
You must have been very convincing.
你一定很有说服力
It's a feminine talent.
这是女性具有的才能
Well, what a waste not to exploit it.
哦,不利用它是一种浪费
I was going to send Sloane to see Mr. Pollock
我打算派斯隆去找波洛克先生
to convince him to return the cipher.
说服他把密文归还
But Sloane has so few subtle qualities.
但是斯隆不够机智
I'm sure the professor would much rather deal with you.
我相信教授宁愿和你打交道
I thought you were jealous of the professor.
我以为你是嫉妒教授
I'm too busy now being jealous of Yussef.
我现在太忙了,嫉妒优素福
- Hello.   - Mr. Pollock.
- 你好  - 波洛克先生
One moment, please, for the Prime Minister.
请等一下,首相跟你讲话
Mr. Pollock.
波洛克先生
Good morning, sir.
早上好,先生
We've been trying to contact you, Mr. Pollock. We were very worried about you.
我们一直设法联系你,波洛克先生。我们真的很为你担心
No more than I was, sir.
不会比我更担心,先生
- Did you get the information?   - No, sir.
- 你得到我们想要的信息了吗？  - 没有,先生
- But you do have the cipher?   - No, sir.
- 但是你一定得到密文了  - 没有,先生
Do you know who does?
你知道谁得到了吗？
- I think so, sir.   - Will you be getting it then?
- 是的,我想是这样,先生  - 那么你会得到它吗？
- No, sir.   - Why is that, Mr. Pollock?
- 不会,先生  - 为什么这样,波洛克先生？
- No guts, sir.   - I beg your pardon?
- 没有勇气,先生  - 请你再说一遍？
As long as you needed someone to sit down and work, I was your man.
只要你需要有人坐下来工作,我是你的人
But the situation has changed somewhat.
但情况有所改变
What you need now is someone with a Ph.D in roughhouse.
你现在需要的是一位能大打出手的哲学博士
I did warn you that it might become dangerous.
我确实警告过你,那可能会变得很危险
Well, dangerous, sir, not lethal.
嗯,危险,先生,不是致命的
Yes. Yes, you are quite right.
是的。是的,你完全正确
I apologize, Mr. Pollock.
我很抱歉,波洛克先生
When one is willing to die for national honor,
当一个人愿意为国家的荣誉而死时
it is hard to remember that other people
他很难想到其他人
have equally important values to live for.
有着同等重要的生活价值
There is no reason why you, an outsider,
没有理由是你,一个局外人
should risk such a sacrifice for another man's country.
应该去为其他人的国家冒牺牲的危险
You... You take unfair advantage, Mr. Prime Minister.
你...你获取了不正当的利益,首相先生
How so?
为什么？
By appealing to a man's better instincts.
通过吸引一个人的本能
- I was confident that you had them.   - Well... very well, sir.
- 我相信你具备那些  - 好吧...很好,先生
Where would you like me to be... murdered this time?
这次你想让我在哪被谋杀？
Try and find the inscription if you can.
如果可以的话,你设法找到的题词
Decipher it, and call me the moment you have.
破译它,然后立刻给我打电话
- Time is getting very short and...   - David. David.
- 时间越来越少  - 戴维。戴维
Thank God you're all right.
谢天谢地你没事
This isn't your house.
嗯,听着,这不是你的家
This is my house, and you weren't invited. So go away.
这是我的家,而且我没邀请你,所以走开
I didn't even know you were alive, but I came to warn you anyway.
我甚至不知道你还活着,但不管怎样我是来提醒你的
About what?
提醒我什么？
Nejim's men are on their way here to get the cipher back.
纳吉姆的人,他们在来这的路上,来拿回密文
- You've got to get away.   - Now slow down a minute.
- 你必须要离开  - 现在慢一点
Aren't you the same Miss Azir
你不是同样的那位阿兹尔小姐吗
who just stood there while your friends tried to kill me?
你朋友要杀我时,你却站在那
Oh, David! You don't think I enjoyed that?
哦,戴维！你不会觉得我愿意那样吧？
- Well, so long as you didn't enjoy it.   - There was nothing I could do.
- 哦,好吧,既然你不愿意  - 我当时毫无办法
You've got to listen to me!
你得听我的
Every time I listen to you, someone either hits me over the head
每次我听你的时候,不是有人打我的头
or tries to vaccinate me.
就是要被打疫苗
Maybe it's time that I called the police.
也许是我叫警察的时候了
You mustn't do that.
你千万不能那样做
What do you suggest then, the Salvation Army?
那你有什么建议,救世军吗？
- Come with me, before it's too late.   - What?
- 现在跟我来,趁还来得及  - 什么？
And wind up back in Yussef Kasim's rumble seat? No, thank you.
然后回到优素福·卡西姆的车后座？不,谢谢
Tell your boyfriend I'm a bad sport.
请告诉你男朋友,我不擅长体育
If I'd let him kill me, I'd never have forgiven myself.
如果我让他杀了,我永远也不会原谅我自己
Yussef is not my boyfriend. I loathe him.
优素福不是我的男朋友,我憎恨他
Of course you do. You just do what he tells you
你当然是。你必须按照他说的做
because he's holding your family hostage back in the old country.
因为他把你祖国的家人当成人质
- How did you know that?   - Oh, come on.
- 你怎么知道的？  - 哦,好吧
I've seen that movie.
我看过那部电影
General Ali Ben Ali,
阿里将军,本·阿里
the man he works for,
他为那个人效力
threatened to kill my mother and sisters
威胁要杀死我的母亲和姐妹
unless I cooperated with him.
除非我跟他合作
And Beshraavi, who's he got, your Uncle Max from Newark?
还有拜士拉维,他找来了你在纽瓦克的叔叔麦克斯吧？
- What do you mean?   - Forget it.
- 你什么意思？  - 哦,算了
If you want to live with Ali Baba and the Forty Thieves, that's your business.
如果你想与阿里巴巴和四十大盗生活,那是你的事情
Do you think I like being near that degenerate?
你觉得我喜欢靠近那个堕落的人吗？
I have to. Don't you understand?
我是迫不得已,你明白吗？
Yussef ordered me to meet him and to cultivate his friendship,
优素福命令我去迎合他,然后培养和他的友谊
so I could report on his actions.
所以我可以报告他的行动
Anyway, the pay is good.
是的,总之报酬优厚
It's not the money. I swear it. It's my family.
不是钱的问题,我发誓。是我的家人
Oh, look, everyone's got problems, including me,
哦,瞧,每个人都有问题,包括我
so I'd just as soon not get mixed up in yours.
所以我只是不想和你混在一起
But you are mixed up in them, whether you like it or not.
但你和他们混在一起了,不管你喜不喜欢
Beshraavi wants to rule our country with his money, General Ali with his guns.
拜士拉维想用他的钱统治我们的国家,阿里将军用他的枪
Both must know what's in that inscription.
他们都必须知道题词的内涵
That means they need you.
那意味着他们需要你
David, you must believe that I hate them both,
戴维,你必须相信,我恨他们两个
that I'm only doing what they want because I have to.
我只是被迫按他们的要求行事
If you can translate the inscription and we can get it to my embassy,
现在,如果你能翻译密文,我们就可以把它交给我的大使馆
we'll both be safe.
我们都会安全
Yeah, well, It sounds reasonable, I guess.
是的,好吧,这,这听起来很合理,我估计
Then... you believe me?
那么...你相信我吗？
In this cynical old world, you have to believe in something.
哦,在这个愤世嫉俗的旧世界,你必须相信一些东西
So, it might as well be you.
如此,这也可能是你
- OK, I'll buy it.   - Thank you.
- 好吧,我赞成  - 谢谢你
Take it easy. I'm not quite myself this morning.
留点神。我今天早上不太舒服
You're wonderful.
你太棒了
Yeah, if I could find my head, I'd go get it examined.
是的,如果我脑袋清醒的话,我会去给它做个检查
If we're going to have visitors, we better get out of here.
如果我们有访客,我们最好离开这
Want to give it to me now?
现在想把它给我吗？
- Give what to you?   - The inscription.
- 给你什么？  - 题词
- I don't have it.   - Well, who does?
- 我没有  - 好吧,谁有？
- You do.   - Me? No, no.
- 你有  - 我？不,不
You've forgotten, Yussef took it from me in the van last night.
你忘了,优素福昨晚在货车上从我这拿走了它
But he couldn't find it.
但他找不到它
Yeah, he found it. He just didn't know that he'd found it.
对,他找到了它。他只是不知道他会找到它
Maybe we can still get it back... with a little help from you.
也许我们还能把它拿回来...需要你的一点帮助
Where's Yussef?
优素福在哪？
It's all right. He's down there.
没事的,他就在下边
OK, where is it?
好的,它在哪？
Over there, I think. Come on.
我想在那边,走吧
Must have had pups during the night.
夜间一定有劣货交易
I'll know it when I see it. He dented it last week.
我看见了就会知道。他上周把它撞瘪了
How? Knocking down an old lady at a crossing?
怎么弄的？在路口撞倒了老太太吗？
There it is.
它在那
Hey, hey.
嗨,嗨
- It's still there.   - I don't see anything.
- 它还在那  - 我什么也没看到
The candy! You are brilliant!
糖果！你真聪明
The result of a clean mind and a healthy body.
纯洁心灵和健康身体的结果
Yussef.
优素福
I've checked all the morning papers. There's not a word.
我查看了所有的报纸,只字未提
- Do you think he's still alive?   - Stop bugging me. How would I know?
- 你认为他还活着吗？  - 别烦我。我怎么知道？
Have you heard from the girl?
有那姑娘的消息吗？她找到了吗？
She'll give me a blast when she knows something.
她一有消息就会提供给我
Oh, no, he's taking it. Why couldn't he be on a diet?
哦,不,他要把它带走。他为什么不节食呢？
What do you know?
你知道什么？
- Thirty-five. Which one is it?   - Number nine.
- 三十五。它是哪个？  - 九号
- You were actually telling the truth.   - What do you mean?
- 你说的是实话  - 你在说什么？
Yussef was here. I was here. The cipher was here.
优素福在这,我在这,密文在这
All you had to do was yell, but you didn't.
你所要做的就是呼喊,可是你没有
That absurd story about your mother and sisters must be true.
那个关于你母亲和姐妹的荒唐的故事一定是真的
- You mean you didn't believe me?   - Not a word.
- 你是说你不相信我吗？  - 我只字未提
- Then why did you come with me?   - I didn't know where the van was.
- 那你为什么跟我来？  - 因为我不知道货车在哪
Miss Azir, I humbly apologize.
阿兹尔小姐,我深表歉意
I don't accept. The least you can do when I tell you something is believe it.
我不接受。至少你要做到当我告诉你一些事情时,你要相信它
With your track record?
包括你过去的记录吗？
Let's go. Be ready to duck.
我们走,注意躲避
- Fourteen.   - I only hope his sweet tooth holds up.
- 十四  - 我只希望他不再喜爱甜食
We're victims of the Establishment.
我们是当权派的受害者
Ask him to move.
为什么不让他走开
It's no use. They can't move, speak or even listen.
没有用。他们不能动,不能说话,甚至不能听
If they do, they're beheaded.
如果他们这样做,他们会被斩首
Oh, nonsense. He's a man, isn't he?
哦,胡说。他是个男人,不是吗？
- Excuse me, soldier.   - He's a guardsman.
- 打扰一下,士兵  - 不对,他是一个卫兵
Excuse me, guardsman.
打扰一下,卫兵
I'm sorry to bother you.
我很抱歉打扰你
I know you're on duty, but...
我知道你在值班,但是...
There is something under your foot that belongs to us.
你脚底下有个东西,我们是东西的主人
OK?
好吗？
Please.
拜托了
Pretty please.
求求你了
David, make him lift his foot!
戴维,让他抬起脚
You've been learning from Nejim.
你在向纳吉姆学习
Fifty-two! You'd think after all that...
五十二！你觉得做了那么多事以后...
Oh, no. He's found it.
哦,不。他发现它了
Sink, sank, sunk.
糟糕,坏了,惨了
- He must be calling Yussef.   - I don't think so.
- 他一定是给优素福打电话  - 哦,我不这么想
He knows Yussef's number.
他知道优素福的电话号码
Keep an eye on Webster.
盯住韦伯斯特
Look here.
看这
Webster sold out to Nejim.
韦伯斯特卖给了纳吉姆
Seems to be a popular indoor sport these days.
这些天似乎有一个流行的室内运动
You're not including me, I hope.
我希望你说的不包括我
Of course not. We're believing you today.
当然不。我们今天相信你
- 3:30, but it doesn't say where.   - It doesn't have to.
- 三点半,但没说在哪  - 没必要说
If he's meeting Nejim at 3:30, there's only one place it can be.
如果他在三点半见纳吉姆,只能有一个地方
In the fifth race the runners are as follows...
第五场比赛的选手如下...
I must go and advise my horse.
我必须去给我的马提供意见
- Are you coming, my love?   - You go, my darling.
- 你来吗,我的宝贝？  - 你去吧,我亲爱的
I think I'll put some money on her.
我想我要在它身上赌一些钱
What an excellent idea. But only to win, of course.
真是个好主意。当然只有赢了
It would be a grave mistake to back another horse at this late stage.
这将是一个严重错误,如果在这最后关头去支持别的马
Well, if it isn't Mr. Dillingham.
嗨,这不是迪林厄姆先生吗
By Jove, it's actually Lady Hetherington-Cartwright.
天啊,那实际上是赫瑟林顿·卡特赖特夫人
- Don't overdo it.   - I didn't know you could.
- 别做得太过火  - 我不知道你可以
I haven't seen Webster.
我还没见过韦伯斯特
He's handing the inscription to Sloane at 3:30 by the winning post.
三点半通过终点时他会给斯隆密文
- Do be a dear, Mr. Dillingworth.   - Ham.
- 一定要做个好人,迪林沃思先生  - 哈姆
Dillingham. Tell me what you fancy for this race.
啊,迪林哈姆。告诉我你对这场比赛的关注点在哪
I'm putting my jolly old shirt on number nine.
好吧,我把我的老本都押在了九号
Keep your eyes on the winning post. You'll have to get it somehow.
请你盯住终点。你必须设法得到它
- And then what?   - Meet at Trafalgar Square at midnight.
- 然后呢？  - 我们午夜在特拉法尔加广场见面
It's been positively smash to have bumped into you this way, old thing.
那样与你见面将会大功告成,老朋友
Do give my regards to your husband next visiting day.
下个参观日务必代我向你的丈夫问候
- Ta-ta.   - Toodle-oo.
- 回头见  - 再见
What odds did you get?
你有几层胜算？
Two to one.
二比一
They're off.
他们出发了
It's Pollock.
那是波洛克
Who is that?
那是谁？
They're turning into the stretch. Three furlongs left to race, and it's...
他们拉开了距离。比赛还剩下六百六十码
That bungling idiot, Sloane.
那个笨拙的傻瓜,斯隆
Darling, we won!
亲爱的,我们赢了！
- Hello?   - Prime Minister Jena, please.
- 你好  - 请找耶拿首相
It's very urgent. This is Mr. Pollock.
情况很紧急。我是波洛克先生
Pollock.
波洛克
Mr. Pollock, what has happened?
波洛克先生,发生了什么事？
Mr. Jena, there's been some trouble.
耶拿先生,有一些麻烦
- A man was killed at Ascot today.   - Yes, I heard.
- 今天有一个人在阿斯科特被杀了  - 是的,我听说了
Have you also heard who it is they think killed him?
你也听说他们觉得把谁杀了吗？
Mrs. Pollock's idiot son, David, that's who. I need your help.
波洛克太太的白痴儿子,戴维。就是他,我需要你的帮助
I don't think there's anything I can do for you right now,
我不认为现在有什么我能为你做的
besides suggesting that you stay clear of the police.
除了那个建议,你要和警察划清界限
Mr. Prime Minister, I don't think I've made myself clear.
首相先生,我不认为现在我自己弄清楚了
Right now I'm wanted for murder.
我被通缉犯有谋杀罪
You're the only one who can explain what I've been doing.
你是唯一可以解释我在做什么的人
But, Mr. Pollock, I thought I'd made myself clear.
但是。波洛克先生,我想我明白了
For security reasons, I have never seen you.
出于安全原因,我从来没去见你
I am not even in England.
我甚至不在英国
Whatever the circumstances, we must disclaim any knowledge of you.
不管什么情况,我和我的大使馆必须否认和你认识
Where are you? Have you the message?
你在哪？你得到信息了吗？
If the message is not deciphered soon, then...
如果我们不能快点把信息破译,那么...
Come here, my darling.
过来,我亲爱的
- I brought you some presents.   - How sweet.
- 我给你带了些礼物  - 好贴心
More shoes?
又增添了鞋子？
But, darling, you've already given me dozens.
但是,亲爱的,你已经给了我几十双
I couldn't resist these.
我无法抗拒这些
Quite a coincidence, Mr. Pollock turning up at the right place and right time.
真是太巧合了,波洛克先生出现在正确的地点和时间
- Don't you think so?   - I would hardly call it a coincidence.
- 你不这么认为吗？  - 我很难称它为巧合
Neither would I. How do you account for it, my flower?
我也不会。你怎么解释它,我的花朵？
He must have been following Yussef's man, the one who was killed.
他肯定在跟踪优素福的人,被杀的那个人
- Do you think so?   - It's the only explanation.
- 你这样认为吗？  - 这是唯一的解释
You wouldn't have mentioned it, of course.
你当然没提到这件事
I?
我吗？
Those are rather attractive, don't you think?
那些相当性感,你不觉得吗？
Exquisite.
精挑细选的
I really must thank whoever was responsible for getting him there.
我真要感谢负责让他到那的人
- Then you wanted him to have it?   - Certainly.
- 那么你想让他得到它？  - 当然
Who else is going to decipher it?
还有谁能破译它？
I want you to find him again,
我想让你再找到他
I want you to stay with him until he finishes his work,
我要你和他呆在一起,直到他完成他的工作
and then I want you to bring the answers to me.
然后我想让你把答案给我
- Is that clear, my angel?   - Very clear.
- 清楚了吗,我的天使？  - 非常清楚
I know that I can trust you to do that for me.
我知道我能相信你会为我这么做
Unless, of course, you're growing weary of my little gifts.
除非是你厌倦了我的小礼物
Oh, and if I don't hear from you by noon tomorrow
哦,如果到明天中午我还没有你的消息
try and think of some remote corner of the world where I won't find you.
试着在世间想出某个偏僻的角落,我不会找到你的地方
I don't think you can... but try.
我不认为你找得到,但试试看
Thank you, sir.
谢谢你,先生
- Mrs. Ragheeb?   - Oh, but, sir...
- 拉吉卜太太？  - 哦,但是,先生...
I must speak to Mrs. Ragheeb.
我必须找拉吉卜太太谈话
Mrs. Ragheeb, I'm an associate of Professor Ragheeb at Oxford.
拉吉卜太太,我是牛津拉吉卜教授的同事
This is tremendously urgent. It's about your husband's... murder.
这件事极为紧迫。这是关于你丈夫的谋杀案
Murder? Why do you say "murder"?
谋杀案？你为什么说“谋杀案”？
Your husband was murdered by some agent of Nejim Beshraavi.
你丈夫被纳吉姆·拜士拉维的特工谋杀了
He was killed for a Hittite inscription. I don't know why.
他是因为一个希泰语题词被杀。我不知道为什么
- I know very little, but I know that.   - No, Amir.
- 我知道的很少,我很清楚这一点  - 不,阿米尔
Mrs. Ragheeb, I know this is a terrible time to trouble you,
拉吉卜太太,我知道这个时间打扰你很令人讨厌
but I've got to know what that inscription means.
但我得知道那个题词的含义
I thought, perhaps, among your husband's notes...
我想也许,在你丈夫的笔记中...
- A Hittite inscription, you say?   - Did he tell you anything about it?
- 你是说一个希泰语题词吗？  - 他有没有告诉你什么？
Show it to me.
让我看看它
Mrs. Ragheeb...
拉吉卜太太
I told him he was mad to meddle in such things.
我告诉过他不要犯傻去插手这种事
Madness and suicide.
疯狂和自杀
And now... he's in there.
而现在...他在那里面
But he must have told you something.
但是他一定告诉过你
He must have mentioned where he got it, who gave it to him.
和提到过一些什么,他从哪得到它的,谁给他的
- We have to know.   - "We"? Who else?
- 我们得知道  - “我们”？还有谁？
A girl. Her family's in great danger.
一个姑娘。她的家人有生命危险
Her mother and sisters, General Ali will kill them.
她的母亲和姐妹,阿里将军威胁要杀他们
- Is the girl named Yasmin Azir?   - Yes.
- 是那个叫亚丝明·阿兹尔的姑娘吗？  - 是的
And she told you that her mother and her sisters are in danger?
她告诉你她母亲和姐妹们有危险吗？
Yes.
是的
Yasmin has no such family, Mr. Pollock.
亚丝明没有这样的家庭,波洛克先生
There is only her father.
她只有父亲
General Ali would never harm him.
而且阿里将军不会伤害他
- Why not?   - Because General Ali is her father.
- 为什么不会？  - 因为阿里将军是她父亲
David, I was so worried about you.
哦,戴维,我很担心你
Oh, you were?
哦,是吗？
The police think you killed Webster. Have you seen the papers?
警察认为你杀了韦伯斯特。你看过报纸吗？
I don't care what they say as long as they spell my name right.
好吧,我不在乎他们说我什么,只要他们写对我的名字
I had a hard time convincing Nejim I had nothing to do with your being at Ascot.
我很难使纳吉姆信服我和你在阿斯科特的出现没有关系
I'm sure that you were very convincing.
我确信你很有说服力
I told him you must have been following Webster,
我告诉他你一定在跟踪韦伯斯特
- but I'm not sure he believed me.   - How could anyone not believe you?
- 但我不确定他是否相信我  - 怎么会有人不相信你
He made me promise to keep you working on the cipher
他要我保证让你继续研究密文
and to call him the moment you've broken it.
你一破译它,我就给他打电话
- Oh, damn.   - What's wrong?
- 哦,见鬼  - 嗯,怎么了？
Nejim had me followed when I left the house but I thought I'd lost them.
当我离开家的时候,纳吉姆在跟踪我,但我以为我甩开了他们
Now they're back again. Duck.
现在他们又回来了,躲避起来
Oh, it's all right. We lost them.
哦,没事了。我们甩开了他们
Next time let me know so I can fasten my seat belt.
是的,好吧。下次要让我知道,这样我就能系紧安全带了
Where is the inscription? May I see it?
题词在哪？我可以看一下吗？
Why do you want to see it?
哦,你为什么想看吗？
I don't know. I've never seen it.
我不知道。我从来没见过它
When you've seen one, you've seen them all.
啊,相信我,它们长得全都一个样
- As long as you have it.   - Well, I don't have it.
- 好吧,只要你拥有它  - 好吧,我,我没有
- What do you mean? Of course you have it!   - Look out!
- 你什么意思？你当然拥有它！  - 当心！
- Would you like me to drive?   - What have you done with it?
- 你想让我开车吗？  - 你把它怎么了,戴维？
Relax. I haven't forgotten your mother and sisters.
现在放松。我没忘记你的母亲和姐妹
- I mailed it to myself.   - Oh, no.
- 我把它寄给自己了  - 哦,不
How will you be able to work on it?
你怎么来研究它？
I won't have to. I know what's in it.
我不需要。我知道里面有什么
What does it mean? Tell me.
那是什么意思？告诉我
It said, "The... plague shall not pass until the swans...
上面说,“嗯...瘟疫是不会过去的,除非天鹅...
fly high in the kingdom of Vesta."
翱翔在女灶神的王国”
- Vesta? What does that mean?   - How should I know?
- 女灶神？那是什么意思？  - 我怎么知道？
My job was to translate it into English.
我的工作是把它翻译成英语,我没有得到结果
Well, I suppose it will mean something to somebody.
好吧,我猜这对某人意味着什么
I'll call the embassy and tell them, but I'd better drop you off first.
我会打电话给大使馆告诉他们,但我最好先让你下车
- Where are you staying?   - Right here with you.
- 你住在哪？  - 在你身边
It's not safe for you to be out on the streets. What if the police stop us?
让你在街上不安全。如果警察拦住我们怎么办？
The way you drive? Why should they stop us?
你开车的方式吗？他们为何拦住我们？
All right, David. I'll look for a phone box.
好吧,戴维。我要找个电话亭
No, no, I'll look. That way maybe we can keep from hitting it.
不,不,我来找。这样我们可以防止撞到它
- Want me to come with you?   - What for?
- 要我和你一起去吗？  - 为什么？
- Think how cozy it would be.   - But so hard to dial.
- 那样多么的亲密无间  - 但是拨号很困难
Don't tell me that the ambassador spoke with you at this hour?
哦,别告诉我大使馆会在这个时候和你谈话
As a matter of fact, he did.
哦,事实上,他谈话了
They are preparing for Mr. Jena's visit tomorrow.
他们在为明天耶拿先生的访问做准备
What did he say?
哦,那他怎么说？
He didn't understand the message. He said to come right over.
他说他不理解那个信息。他说马上来
Er... it's all right. You can get out here. I'll meet you later.
嗯...没关系。你在这下车吧。过一会儿我来找你
- Why?   - Stop asking so many questions.
- 为什么？  - 哦,请不要问这么多问题
There are police at the embassy. They'll recognize you.
有大使馆的警察,他们会认出你
Do you want to be arrested for murder?
你想因谋杀而被逮捕吗？
All right. I'll meet you in Knightsbridge at the Kelly Hotel.
好吧。我会在凯利酒店的骑士桥见你
I'm registered in the name of O'Malley.
我以奥马利的名义在那登记
- O'Malley?   - There's a discount if you're Irish.
- 奥马利？  - 是的。如果你是爱尔兰人,会有折扣
Follow that car.
跟上那辆车
All my life I've waited for somebody to say that.
我这一辈子都等着有人说那句话
Thanks, guv. I enjoyed that.
谢谢,先生。我很乐意
Yussef?
优素福？
Yasmin! Get down!
亚丝明！下来！
- David, you followed me.   - No, I didn't.
- 戴维,你在跟踪我  - 不,我没有
You went to the embassy and I came here to my hotel.
你去大使馆了,而我来这是为了去我的酒店
There. Over the wall.
那边,墙上
Wait!
等等！
Down here.
到这来
Can't say I care much for your embassy.
我不能说很喜欢你的大使馆
David, I wasn't deceiving you. I had to find out what the message means.
戴维,我没骗你。我得弄清楚这个信息的意思
Yussef is the only one who knows. That's why I came here.
而优素福是唯一一个知道的人。那是我来这的原因
Not one of your brighter ideas.
你不是一个好主意
- You stay here.   - David!
- 你呆在这  - 戴维！
Oh, David! Oh, David!
哦,戴维！哦,戴维！
I couldn't let you die without hearing the end of your story.
我不能让你没听到故事结局之前死
Come on!
快点！
But it's true. Everything. I swear it.
但这是真的。所有事情,我发誓
As true as your poor old mother and your three sisters?
你可怜的老母亲和三姐妹也是真的吗？
- Of course.   - I went to Mrs. Ragheeb.
- 当然  - 我去拉吉卜太太那了
- Oh, no.   - She was very well-informed about you.
- 哦,不  - 她对你很了解
You told her you and I were working together?
你告诉她你和我在一起吗？
- Naturally.   - No wonder.
- 理所当然地  - 怪不得
No wonder what?
怪不得什么？
She'd say anything to keep you from trusting me.
她说这些只是不想让你信任我
She's an agent of Yussef's, like her husband. Don't you see what you did?
她像她丈夫一样,是优素福的特工。你不明白你干了什么吗？
The moment you let her know I was double-crossing them,
你让她知道我出卖了他们的那一刻
she called Yussef to warn him.
她给优素福打电话让他警惕
So he lured me to the construction site, to kill me!
所以他引诱我到施工现场,要杀了我
What is there about you that makes you so hard to believe?
你有种什么样的特质使你很难被相信？
Perhaps it's because I'm such a terrible liar.
也许因为我是一个糟糕的骗子
But never with you, of course.
但当然从来没有骗过你
I wish I could say the same.
我希望我也能这样说
"The plague shall not pass until the swans fly high in the kingdom of Vesta."
“瘟疫是不会过去的,除非天鹅翱翔在女灶神的王国”
You made it up?
那是你瞎编的吗？
- What's the real message?   - I haven't worked it out yet.
- 那真正的信息是什么？  - 我还没把它想出来
We'll have to do something. I packed a suitcase. It's in the back.
好吧,我们得做点什么。我收拾好了行李,它在后面
I can't very well go back to my house. Nejim isn't the understanding type.
我没法回到我的房子。纳吉姆不是那种理解型的
Haven't you any ideas?
你没有什么主意吗？
Yeah.
有
Darling?
亲爱的
I got the message.
我得到消息了
Yasmin!
亚丝明！
Good morning.
早上好
Good morning, my darling.
早上好,我亲爱的
You pass bachelor's requirement number one. You're lovely in the morning.
你是通过学士学位要求的头号人物。你早上很可爱
I was dreaming of someone much more romantic. You.
我梦见有一个人更加浪漫。你
No, come back here. I have something else.
不,过来。我还有些话
I've cracked the cipher.
我破解了密文
David, that's wonderful. What does it mean?
戴维,那真是太好了。它的意思是什么？
It's a phony, 100 per cent phony.
这是赝品,百分之百赝品
It isn't Hittite. It's an ordinary, common-or-garden grade-school code.
这根本不是希泰语。这是一个普通的,常见的学校密码
- Look. Here, you want these?   - No, certainly not.
- 现在看,喏,你要这些吗？  - 不,当然不
You see, bird sign, bird sign, bird sign.
你看,鸟的标志,鸟的标志,鸟的标志
Sex differentiation factor.
有性别差异的因素
You mean it's dirty?
你是说它很脏？
No, a three-year-old child could understand.
不是,三岁的孩子都能理解
Female bird: goose. Female bird: goose. Male bird: gander.
雌鸟,雌鹅。雄鸟,公鹅
"Whither do you wender..."
“你向何处wender...”
- No, that's "wander".   - Wander.
- 不,那是“wander(游荡)”  - 游荡
- "Upstairs, downstairs..."   - "Or in my lady's chamber."
- 对。“楼上,楼下...”  - “或者在我夫人的房间”
- What does that mean?   - I don't know.
- 那是什么意思？  - 哦,我不知道
We've got Beshraavi, the British constabulary,
我们有拜士拉维,英国警察部队,
the whole human race howling after our blood
全人类在我们的血液中嚎叫
just for a lousy nursery rhyme.
只是为了一个糟糕的童谣
- It's got to mean something.   - It must.
- 它肯定意味着什么  - 那是必然的
- Who wrote it in the first place?   - Ragheeb, I imagine.
- 当初是谁写的？  - 我猜想是拉吉卜
Exactly. Ragheeb.
正是拉吉卜
"Upstairs, downstairs... in my lady's chamber."
“楼上,楼下...在我夫人的房间”
Mrs. Ragheeb must have the answer.
拉吉卜太太一定有答案
She couldn't have. She would have told Yussef.
但她不可能有。他肯定会告诉优素福的
That's right too.
这么说也是对的
When I showed her a copy of it, she tore it up.
当我给她看它的副本时,她把它撕了
She looked at it, and she didn't give a damn.
她看着它,她毫不在乎它
- Wow!   - David... what are you talking about?
- 哇！  - 戴维...为什么我不知道你在说什么？
A copy of the message means nothing, the translation means nothing.
信息的副本豪无意义,翻译豪无意义
The message is a screen. It's a doodle.
信息是表面,它是一个掩蔽,它是一个涂鸦
All that matters is the original piece of paper.
那张纸的原件决定一切
- The original?   - Of course. It isn't the cipher.
- 原件？  - 当然。不是那个密文
It's something else on that paper. Something underneath the cipher.
是那张纸上的一些其他东西。密文下面的一些东西
Arise, arise, oh, my beloved.
有眉目了,有眉目了。哦,我亲爱的
To the Hammersmith Post Office.
去哈默史密斯邮局
Have you got it?
你拿到了吗？
Don't you trust me with anything?
你为什么都不相信我呢？
No watermark.
没有水印
- What do you see?   - Gander, goosy, goosy.
- 你看到什么了？  - 雄鹅,雌鹅,雌鹅
Just keep your eyes on the road.
你看好路就行了
It must be here someplace.
它一定在什么地方
Are you burning it?
你在烧它吗？
That's how you detect invisible ink.
这是检测隐形墨水的方法
- Weren't you ever in the Boy Scouts?   - I flunked the physical.
- 你没参加过童子军吗？  - 我物理考试不及格
You should have tried my troop. We'd have waived it.
你应该试试我的部队。我们不得不放弃它
Wait, wait! Stop the car!
等等,等等！停车！
- What are you doing?   - I'm about to invent the wheel.
- 你在做什么？  - 我要发明轮子了
Well, there it goes.
好吧,它不见了
- No, no, wait. Look!   - I don't see anything.
- 没有,没有,等等。看！  - 我什么也没看见
The eye. The eye of the third bird.
眼睛。第三只鸟的眼睛
What's that?
那是什么？
A microdot.
一个缩微影印文件
- What do you see?   - Take a look.
- 你看到什么了？  - 看一看
- She's a beauty, isn't she?   - She certainly is.
- 她真是一个美女,不是吗？  - 她当然是
But the microscope's a trifle small. Haven't you anything larger?
但显微镜有点小。你有没有大点的
Certainly, sir.
当然,先生
So that's what they wanted Yussef to know.
所以这是他们想让优素福知道的
Something on this order, sir?
是要这种吗,先生？
I'm afraid not. Haven't you anything larger?
我恐怕不行。有没有更大点的？
I'll look, sir.
我看看,先生
What do we do now?
我们现在做什么？
It says when, but it doesn't say where. When is the 18th?
上面说了什么时间,但没说什么地点。十八号是周几？
Monday was the 14th. Tuesday, Wednesday...
我们看看。十四号周一,周二,周三...
- It's today.   - Today?
- 是今天  - 今天？
Come on!
快点！
This is the largest we have, sir. Shall I...
这是我们最大的,先生。要不要我来...
Hey, David, look!
嗨,戴维,看！
- Oh, no! Do something!   - Lift it out of the way?
- 哦,不！想个办法！  - 你想把它从路上挪开吗？
I don't care. Do anything!
我不管,随便怎么做！
Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen.
下午好,女士们,先生们
Mr. Jena will be happy to answer your questions now.
现在耶拿先生很高兴回答你们的问题
All right, mate. Lots of room. That's it.
可以,老兄。很多空间,很多空间。就这样
Keep on going. Lots of leeway back there.
继续走,后面有很多余地
Bring her on back, mate. OK, fine. Plenty of leeway.
往后来,老兄。好,很好。那有足够的余地
Plenty of leeway. Lots of room. Right on back. Good.
有足够的余地。有很多空间。好极了,向后,好
Right on back, mate. Right on back.
好极了,向后,老兄。好极了,向后
Fine, fine. Good. Plenty of room, mate.
很好,很好,好。那有很多空间,老兄
That's good.
很好
Thanks, mate.
谢谢,老兄
This is your first visit to England. What are your first impressions?
这是您第一次访问英国,首相先生。你的第一印象是什么？
We could use some of your English rain in our dry country.
我们可以把你们英国的雨水利用在我们干旱的国家
In our country, there's a great deal of oil and very little water.
在我们国家,有大量的石油和很少的水
A highly inflammable situation.
高度易燃的形势
All right, Hemsley.
可以了,赫姆斯利
Water remains our most serious problem.
水仍然是我们最严重的问题
To paraphrase Marie Antoinette:
用玛丽·安托瓦内特的话来说：
I can hardly say of my people, "Let them drink oil."
我真不知怎么向我的人民交待,“让他们喝石油”
May I see your press card, please, sir?
我能看看你的记者证吗,先生？
Diners Club? I'm afraid I don't recognize you.
食客俱乐部？我恐怕我不认识你
We're doing a piece on the Arabic cuisine.
我们在做一个阿拉伯菜肴
- I'm sorry, sir. It's not on my list.   - Get out of the way.
- 对不起,先生。我恐怕这不在我的名单上  - 你要是不让开,可要想好了
I'm sorry, sir.
对不起,先生
Would you comment on the treaty you intend signing?
你打算明天签订你所评论的条约吗？
You've been misinformed, sir. I shall not sign the treaty.
我得说很抱歉,你弄错了,先生。我不会签署条约
- Listen!   - Let us through!
- 听着！  - 让我们过去！
- He's about to be killed!   - I hardly think so, this is England.
- 那个人要被杀害了！  - 我不这么想,先生。这是英国
I have studied the terms of the treaty most carefully,
我极为精细地研究了条约的条款
and I could not, in good conscience...
而且我不能签,凭良心说...
They have fought too long and hard...
他们历经了漫长而艰难的奋斗...
Please! Let us through, please!
拜托！请让我们过去！
What is happening?
发生了什么事？
- Mr. Pollock?   - I'm sorry, sir. Are you all right?
- 波洛克先生？  - 对不起,先生。你还好吗？
It appears that I am. What happened?
看起来我很好。发生了什么事？
I was a little late deciphering the message. That's what.
我把那条信息破译出来得有点晚了。没什么了
- Here. Let me help you up.   - Thank you.
- 这,让我扶你起来  - 谢谢
Mr. Pollock was brilliant. He deserves a medal.
波洛克先生很出色。他应该得到一枚奖章
Who is responsible for this? Do you know?
谁为此负责？你知道吗？
Yes, sir. Nejim Beshraavi.
是的,先生。纳吉姆·拜士拉维
Beshr... Mr. Pollock, I must speak with you.
拜士拉...波洛克先生,我必须跟你谈谈
Excuse me. Excuse me. Come, Mr. Prime Minister. The car is waiting.
劳驾,劳驾,劳驾。来,首相先生,车正在等着
- I must speak with Mr. Pollock.   - There's no time.
- 我必须跟波洛克先生谈谈  - 没时间了
We don't know who else here might be involved.
首相,我们不知道这里还有谁参与了
I must speak to Mr. Pollock!
不着急,我必须跟波洛克先生谈谈！
Come on.
快走
They did it. After all that, they did it. We just stood there.
他们做到了。毕竟,他们做到了。我们只是站在那
- Where are we going?   - We have to find Jena.
- 我们去哪？  - 我们必须找到耶拿
- Did I understand you to say...   - That wasn't Jena.
- 我理解你是说...  - 快点,那不是耶拿
- It sounded like you said...   - I tell you, it wasn't!
- 这听起来像你说的...  - 我告诉你,那不是
It looked very much like him, but it wasn't Jena.
那看起来像他,很像他,但那不是耶拿
It was Hassan Jena. I know him.
那是哈桑·耶拿。我认识他
- Oh!   - He knows me.
- 哦！  - 他认识我
I've spoken to him many times. He came to Oxford.
我和他谈过很多次。他来牛津看过我
Jena's never set foot in England before today.
在今天之前,耶拿从来没踏足过英国
He wanted people to think that. He was here.
他希望人们那样认为。但他在这
He's the one who sent me to Beshraavi in the first place.
是他当初派我来拜士拉维这的
That man? The one who was shot?
那个人？那个被枪杀的人吗？
Yes. Now do you believe me?
是的。现在你相信我了吗？
- Why didn't you tell me?   - I never knew who you were.
- 为什么你没告诉我？  - 因为我从来不知道你是谁
That's why he looked so frightened.
那就是为什么他看上去很害怕
Nejim hired him to impersonate Jena,
纳吉姆雇用他冒充耶拿
only he neglected to mention that part of his job was to be murdered.
只是他有意地没有提到他的一部分工作就是被人谋杀
We have to find the real Jena. Come on.
我们必须找到真正的耶拿,快点
You expect me to believe that nonsense?
你指望我相信那些废话吗？
- What proof do you have?   - He didn't recognize me.
- 你有什么证据？  - 他没认出我
But... Wait... Why should he recognize you?
可是...等等...他为什么要认出你？
Yasmin, are you trying to tell me something?
亚丝明,你是想告诉我什么吗？
I am a spy.
我是间谍
Hey. Wait!
嗨,等等！
- Can you prove that statement?   - Do you think we carry calling cards?
- 我猜你能证明那种说法？  - 你认为我们带名片吗？
- Then why didn't you tell me?   - You wouldn't have believed me.
- 哦,那你为什么不告诉我？  - 你不会相信我
- Where are we going?   - I want to see where it happened.
- 我们去哪？  - 我想看看在哪发生的
Where what happened?
在哪,发生了什么？
Did you record the Prime Minister's arrival on tape?
你记录首相到达时的录像了吗？
- Yes.   - Run it for me.
- 是的  - 放给我看
The Prime Minister's life may depend on it.
首相的性命也许要取决于它
- You're a bit late. He's been shot.   - Do as I say.
- 你有点晚了,他已经被枪杀了  - 照我说的做
- Is that tape ready to roll yet?   - It's all set.
- 那盘磁带准备好了吗？  - 都准备好了
Put it up on the monitors.
把它从显示器里放出来
- Which one is that?   - The real one. It has to be.
- 哪一个是？  - 真正的一个,那个必须是
There was no way to get to him before this.
在这之前没有办法找到他的
Yes, it's Jena. Those are his favorite slippers.
是的,那是耶拿。哪些是他最喜欢的拖鞋
Can you see what's happening inside the car?
你能看到车内发生了什么吗？
The windows are too dark.
窗户太暗
Hold that. Can you freeze it?
别动。你能停止吗？
Look, the shoes are different.
看这,鞋子是不同的
He's not wearing slippers anymore. That's where it happened. In the car.
他不再穿拖鞋了。那就是发生地点,在车里
We've got to find it.
我们得找到它
She's a government spy.
她是政府间谍
Look.
看
Come on.
来
Give me a hand, will you?
帮我一把,好吗？
You seriously think...
你真的认为...
What else would they have done? Left him in the airport?
我们还会做什么？把他留在机场了吗？
It's the treaty, isn't it?
这是条约,不是吗？
If it had gone through, Nejim would have been ruined.
如果达成了协议,纳吉姆就遭殃了
- Jena was going to sign it?   - That's why they needed a substitute.
- 而耶拿要签署它吗？  - 但你不明白吗？这就是他们为什么需要一个替身
To denounce the treaty before the assassination.
在暗杀前通告废除条约
I have a vivid imagination.
我有着丰富的想像力
I must say, I never saw myself unpacking a prime minister.
我必须说,我从来没见过自己给首相开箱子
Our life expectancy may be nil, but I'd like you to know this has been
我们的寿命可能成为零,但我想让你知道,这是
a very real, warm, human experience.
非常真实,温暖的人生经验
It's uncanny.
这太不可思议了
What is it? Where am...
怎么回事？我在哪...
You're among friends, sir. At least for the next 30 seconds.
都是自己人,先生。至少在接下来的三十秒内
- Are you all right?   - I think so.
- 你没事吧？  - 我想是的
- Is that you, Miss Azir?   - Let's get him out.
- 是你吗,阿兹尔小姐？  - 我们把他弄出去
Ploy number one.
策略一
We've got him, sir.
我们抓到他了,先生
It's about time you did something right. Well, get him out!
你应该做正确的事情的时间到了。好吧,把他弄出来
Hey, you two! Lend a hand here. And you!
嗨,你们两个！来这帮我一把。还有你！
Undo these chains.
解开这些锁链
Put it down! Open it, Sloane.
把它放下！打开它,斯隆
Imbecile. Must you mismanage everything?
蠢货。你一定要把一切都处置失当吗？
Down! Flat! Now!
卧倒！趴下！现在！
Come on! Run for it!
快点！躲开它！
Wait!
等等！
- Can you ride, Mr. Prime Minister?   - You ask that of an Arab?
- 你会骑马吗,首相先生？  - 你向阿拉伯人问这个问题
- What do you want?   - We, er... er...
- 你们想干什么？  - 我们,嗯...嗯...
You can't ride in that skirt.
你穿这条裙子骑不了马
Hup!
哈！
- Are you all right, sir?   - Yes, thank you.
- 你没事吧,先生？  - 没事,谢谢
That way!
那条路！
I don't see what he can do now.
我不知道他现在能做什么
He'll think of something.
哦,他会想办法
I knew you couldn't keep a good man down.
我知道你不能让好人失望
There!
在那！
Get them, Sloane! This time get them!
抓住他们,斯隆！这次抓住他们！
David!
戴维！
- Are you all right?   - No. I'm ashamed of myself.
- 你还好吗？  - 不。我为自己感到羞耻
- I ride better than that.   - Come on!
- 我骑得比那好  - 快点！
This side!
这边！
Those stairs must lead somewhere.
那些楼梯一定通向某处
Are you sure?
你确定吗？
If they don't, watch out for the last one.
如果它们不是,注意最后一个
Here comes old Eagle-Eye.
老鹰的眼睛盯上这了
This is like a recurring dream I used to have.
这就像一个我曾经反复做过的梦
- How did it end?   - Don't ask.
- 它的结局如何？  - 别问
Here goes.
从这走
Don't, David. Please, don't. You'll be a sitting duck.
不行,戴维。拜托,别这样。你会成为瓮中之鳖
How come my recurring dream never ended this way?
我反复做过的梦为何不是这种结局？
I don't know. Mine always did.
我不知道。我的总是这样
I guess I just travel in better dreams.
我猜我只是在好梦中旅行
Do I have your... solemn pledge that you'll never spy again?
你能向我...郑重承诺你再也不做间谍了吗？
- Only on you.   - Oh, swell.
- 只对你  - 嗯,非常棒
Hey!
嗨！
You clumsy idiot! Oh, it's you, Mr. Pollock.
你这个笨拙的蠢货！哦,是你,波洛克先生
Oh, hello, Fanshaw.
哦,你好,范肖
David... you can swim, can't you?
戴维...你会游泳,是吗？
Sorry. Not a stroke.
抱歉,我一点也不会
David!
戴维！
Here we are again, taking a bath together.
我们又在一起洗了个澡
David, you lied to me!
戴维,你骗了我！
Sure. It was my turn.
当然。轮到我了